COLLIN KUDAKWASHE MUTAURWA

Email: kmutaurwa1@gmail.com · Phone: +44 7732076426

I'm a creative computer scientist with extensive experience in system design and analysis. Excellent experience in product design blending in solutions architecture principles and software engineering and programming languages relevant to client's product success. I'm a good team player who can manage multiple priorities simultaneously.

Objectives

- a. To acquire a challenging position in an environment where I can best utilize my problem solving skills and education.
- b. To adapt to the rapid changes in technology and be able to satisfy customer ever changing needs and desires.
- c. Contribute to innovative, groundbreaking software solutions that meet business demand for agility, mobility and a great cloud experience.

EXPERIENCE

NOV 2020 – JULY 2023

INTEGRATIONS ENGINEER, ECONET WIRELESS GROUP – ECOCASH HOLDINGS

- Worked with Ecocash APIs for integrations with various banks in Zimbabwe CBZ, First Capital, Stanbic etc. Thus, B2W and W2B -Bank to wallet and Wallet 2 Bank services that connects with the Bank, core application and postilion nodes, including for Auto stock creation API.
- Worked with Postilion transaction analysis from ZimSwitch Exposures and banking services for transactions that failed to make auto reversals or those that time out in transit. Hence using Postilion console and interface for analysis with LIQUID TELECOMS technical team members in trouble shooting sessions.
- Worked with Paymentology QR MASTER CARD & ECOCASH DEBIT CARDS Integrations
 on setting up channels for the complete transactional flow and testing the validity of
 APIs in use between Ecocash and TUTUKA before implementation.
- Experience with performing DR (Data Recovery) Drill runbooks on migrating and replicating servers to secondary sites in case of fail-over solutions on production during high traffic. Created virtual IPs and policies for various pool members on LB -Load balancer using defined SNAT ip on specific subnets.
- Worked with Ecocash APIs for integrations with the Bill payments projects on *151*100#. It's an integrated platform for bill payments which allows seem less transactions to be processed without issues. I'm also part of the support team on configurations of the platform upon deployments of all 3rd party billers.

- Worked with resolutions concerning Ecocash callbacks that could have been stuck from RabbitMQ or other workstation nodes responsible pushing callback responses.
- Have worked with RabbitMQ queuing broker. Being able to create exchanges and bind queues defined from consumers.
- Have also worked with the configurations and productions of new Short Codes on the ECOCASH USSD platform, Mars USSD and ECOCASH CHATBOT, which is a new development to the organization.
- Worked on Whitelisting UAT mobile numbers for 3rd party clients to be able to transact flawlessly on the ECOCASH UAT platforms.
- Worked with Voucher Management System (VMS) under Cassava Smartech for retail markets in Zimbabwe.
- Identify bug errors and solutions to the already existing Software Packages in Production environment.
- Created configurations on F5 LOAD BALANCER (LB) on distributing traffic to other servers on Virtual IPS and creating SNAT and policies on pushing traffic and also creating host domain names to be used on other servers. Managing SSL certificates from different domains. Worked on routing traffic pool servers
- Provide resolutions to integration issues on UAT and PRODUCTION Environments from XML, JSON HTTP requests.

Dec 2020 – JUNE 2023

SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT, RIGHT BANK PRIVATE LIMITED

- Developed Execution plan on the path of the project development process with the software developers and product development team.
- -Migrated company projects to cloud AWS EC2 instances and configure AMI instances.
- -Created IAM policies, ROLES and user management for delegated users within AWS specified region.
- -Checked on the daily tasks assigned to every team member from administration to software development team.
- -Developed the blueprint of the product to the market. As a company the mission was to develop a virtual bank and mobile wallet that people could use to transact between bank and personal mobile wallet.
- Designed data and business process flow diagrams and system architecture of the complete product.
- -Designed product UML models on the notion of showing conceptual associations and behaviour of the complete product structure.
- -Create and design new solutions, applying theoretical processes of Software Development Cycle in order to analyze, test and assess software solutions.

- -Develop key performance measures for data integration and quality.
- -Assist & support teams (mainly Development and QA) and provide mentoring expertise to developer.
- Work closely with the project teams as outlined in the SDLC methodology providing guidance in implementing solutions at various stages of projects.

AUGUST 2019 – MARCH 2020 SOFTWARE DEVELEOPER, INTEOPTIMUS PLC

- -Provide technical input to the IT strategic roadmap.
- -Help design and architect the process and technology infrastructure to support production, development, test, and experimental platforms for business customers.
- Created android-based product system for crossroad micro finance institution for loan applications for civil servants. It integrated with payment gateways and SMS APIs for smooth delivery of the service to customers.
- -Demonstrate broad solutions technical leadership, impacting significant technical direction, exerting influence outside of the immediate team and driving change.
- Developed Native android MOBILE APP for Chisipiti Water Delivery Company for the convenience of the community for ordering water to their homes without much effort.
- -Collaborated on company future projects and Innovations.
- -Worked with CHATAPI for WhatsApp Chatbot creation for E Yellow Pages company for their ecommerce company. -Worked with InfoBip services on SMS Gateway API Implementation thus for inbound and outbound channels.
- Participate and lead in design sessions, demos and prototype sessions, testing and training workshops with business users and other IT associates.

JAN 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2017

SOFTWARE DEVELEOPER, FIF DIGITAL MARKETING CONSULTANCY

- Developed microservices and web services (incl. REST/SOAP/XML).
- -Developed web and mobile app for Loyalty system with various payments API and SMS Gateway (Info BIP).
- -Initiate, develop, and lead new solutions demonstrations/proofs of concept on some of the projects.
- Designed a prototype loyalty web system for PSMAS Zimbabwe for creating coupons, vouchers and loyalty points.
- -Experience in system quality assurance and testing bringing a strong focus on voice of the customer into the software development function to ensure product and customer success.
- Built databases and table structures following [Type] architecture methodology for web applications.
- Employed knowledge of relational database concepts and PL/SQL coding to produce highly efficient data systems.
- -Have worked Samsung Beacons devices with compressive API on broadcasting Ads for in stores marketing.

- Integrated the UI, DB, Java, PHP and other modules for a working web application.

Project, tools and APIs

- Experience with performing DR (Data Recovery) Drill runbooks on migrating and replicating servers to secondary sites in case of fail-over solutions on production during high traffic. Created virtual IPs and policies for various pool members on LB -Load balancer using defined SNAT ip on specific subnets.
- On DevOps I have worked with Kibana-Open search Monitoring tool for visuals on graphs and monitoring of incoming traffic and outgoing traffic from different servers of USSD gateways and Cassava payment gateways. Severs.
- I have worked with Open search and Graylog for checking application integration errors on projects from production live env.
- On DevOps I have worked with Ansible on automated deployments of projects in production from Tests UAT to production.
- On DevOps I have worked with AWS platform on deploying EC2 instances and S3 buckets. Also setting up ALB and NLB across various instances. Configured routes for allowed incoming traffic and outgoing traffic. Have also tested Lambda functions, RDS services and postgres. I have also used IAM roles and on creation organizational accounts.
- GIKKO And Message Bird SMS API For Outbound Messages.
- Google Distance Matrix API For Travel Distance and Matrix of Origins and Destinations.
- Ngrok Tunneling for Changing Localhost to Server State.
- SMS Bot (Ecommerce for Orders) For Yellow Pages Using SMS API 2 Way Channel.
- Developed Native android mobile app with INTELLI J for Chisipiti Water Delivery Company for the convenience of the community for ordering water to their homes without much effort.
- Have worked with REST and SOAP API integrations tests.
- Have worked with F5 Load Balancer for routing traffic from 3rd party companies to
 Econet local servers. The traffic from internet will be redirected from 3rd party then it
 will be going via F5 then F5 LB routes to individual servers on a round robin basis. It was
 also used for creating routing policies and for creating virtual lps for individual servers
 created.
- Have worked with Comviva Flares Gateway for creating USSD shorts codes from various Econet subsidiary companies. Short codes for ECOCASH FCA Wallet, Mars, Vaya, Bill payments, ecocash promotions etc.
- Have worked with MYSQL WORKBENCH for all sql queries.
- Have worked with DBeaver for all sql issues on ORACLE, POSTGRES, Mysql, from different sections across the company.
- Have with SQLDEVELOPER for mysql queries and creation of Database views.
- Creation Have worked with Beacons for in stores Ads on marketing campaigns.

EDUCATION

DECEMBER 2022'
MBA, UNIVERSITY OF ZIMBABWE

NOVEMBER 2018'

BARCHELOR'S HONORS DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, BINDURA UNIVERSITY

Thesis: Automated Timetable System using memetic Algorithms

LANGUAGE: ENGLISH (IELTS)

SKILLS: PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES, CMS AND DATABASE MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS

JAVA

PHP(+LARAVEL)

• C++

Java Android

Octave -Machine Learning

• C#

RDMS- ORACLE, POSTGRES, MYSQL, MONGO DB, Amazon services (AWS) AURORA

SOFT SKILLS

- Chess Ability to work quickly and independently with little oversight
- Strong organizational research skills able to gather and analyze qualitative & quantitative role impact feedback.
- Exceptional communication skills. Demonstrable ability to communicate complex concepts to business and technical audiences.
- Ability to connect technology with measurable business value.
- Broad technical knowledge of industry and Technology trends and a strong external perspective of developments in Technology.

ACTIVITIES

To be part of a dynamic and innovative organization participating in its growth and enhancing my professionalism. I enjoy working with people from all walks of life. I enjoy following topical issues and current affairs. I am an avid chess and basketball player. I joined toastmasters club as secretary of ceremonies during high school and I'm a member of Rotaract club Harare west.